marinabaysands.com 2019-12-24

# Privacy Policy | Marina Bay Sands

## Application of This Policy

Marina Bay Sands Pte Ltd and MBS Retail Management Company Pte Ltd (collectively, “MBS”, “our”, “we” or “us”) are subsidiaries of Las Vegas Sands Corp (“Sands”). Sands operates several resort hotel and casino properties in the United States and abroad.  This Privacy Policy is for Singapore and applies to personal data collected, stored, disclosed and/or processed by MBS in Singapore. Sands also owns and operates properties abroad (collectively, the “Non-Singapore Sands Properties,” and together with MBS, the “Sands Properties”).  Information on all Sands Properties is available on Sands’ primary website, sands.com. From there, you may access our property-specific websites and the privacy policies that are linked thereto. This Privacy Policy applies to websites owned and operated by MBS or other websites on which this Privacy Policy, or a link to this Privacy Policy, appears as well as activities at the Sands Properties to the extent Sands notifies you of such activities being subject to this Privacy Policy.  

This Policy is based on the Singapore Personal Data Protection Act 2012 (“PDPA”) and all the associated regulations and guidelines as may from time to time be issued by the Personal Data Protection Commission (“PDPC”) of Singapore.  In jurisdictions outside of Singapore, Sands’ practices may be subject to different or more restrictive local laws.  For information regarding Sands’ data collection and privacy policies at the Non-Singapore Sands Properties, please review the privacy policies available at those property-specific websites.

By visiting or using the MBS website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. Please review this Privacy Policy carefully before visiting or using our website, or otherwise providing us with any of your personal data. 

Unless you opt-out and instruct us otherwise, MBS does and will continue to share the personal data that it collects from you with other of Sands’ subsidiaries, including those who own and operate the Non-Singapore Sands Properties, as permitted under applicable law and the PDPA. Personal data that we collect or store in jurisdictions outside of Singapore may, subject to applicable law and the PDPA, be transferred to and used by MBS or other jurisdictions.  Similarly, personal data that MBS collects or stores may, subject to applicable law and the PDPA, be transferred to and used by us outside of Singapore.  When personal data is collected by MBS or transferred to MBS, it will be treated according to the privacy practices set forth in this Privacy Policy.

## **Note to EU and Non-EU Residents**

The Company respects all individuals’ privacy rights under all the laws that apply to it, all over the world.  We work to comply with privacy laws, including, but not limited to, any right you may have if you live in or visit the United States, Singapore, or Macao where our properties are located.  

The Company voluntarily tries to accommodate privacy requests made by individuals.  Each request is evaluated to determine whether it can be accommodated without violating legal obligations and without creating a risk to the security or integrity of the other information we hold.

For residents of the European Union (“EU”), European Economic Area (“EEA”), and Switzerland, the Company recognises the legal privacy protections afforded to individuals located in the EEA, the EU, and Switzerland, with regard to personal data.  For more information about this, please read the **_Notice to Residents of the EU, EEA, and Switzerland._** provided below.

## Personal Data We Collect and Use

**General Information**

When you use the Internet, your computer may transmit certain information to the servers that host the websites you visit.  The information may include the type of Internet browser you are using, the type of computer operating system you are using, your Internet Portal (IP) address, the pages you visited on our websites, and how you arrived at our websites.  When you visit our websites, we collect this information, and we use this information to create a better user experience, to identify areas for improvement on our websites, to enhance the security of our systems, and to provide information on our special offers and promotions.

**Cookies and Other Internet Technologies**

When you visit our website, we may assign your computer one or more “cookies”. By accessing our website, you agree that we can place cookies on your device.

_What Are Cookies?:_ A “cookie” is a small text file that a website can place on your computer to store your preferences.  Cookies are not personally identifiable by themselves, but they can be linked to personal data you provide to us.

_How We Use Cookies_ : We may use cookies so that we can improve your online experience, including to detect your browser’s capabilities, to track ads we display to you, to store login and purchase information of your choice, to present advertising and other content on our website that is tailored to your web preferences and usage patterns, and to generate statistics on website usage. 

_How We Use Internet Technologies:_ In addition to cookies, we may also use other internet technologies such as web beacons, pixel tags and other similar technologies to deliver or communicate with cookies and track your use of our website.  We also may include web beacons in e-mail messages or newsletters to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon, and how.  The information we obtain in this manner enables us to customize the services we offer and measure the overall effectiveness of our online content, advertising campaigns, and the products and services we offer through our website.  By accessing our website and agreeing to receive our e-mail messages or newsletters, you agree that we can use other internet technologies such as those mentioned above on your device.

_Your Control of Our use of Cookies_ : You have many choices on how to manage cookies on your device.  Most web browsers allow some control of cookies through your browser settings.  Generally, you may block or delete cookies from your system, or set your browser to prevent cookies from being placed on your devices. If you do this, however, you may have to manually adjust preferences every time you visit our websites and it may not be possible to use the full functionality of our websites.  To learn more about your ability to manage cookies, please consult the privacy features in your browser.  Alternatively, you may opt out of cookies and advertising related to the same by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>.  

_How Third Parties Use Cookies and Other Internet Technologies_ : Our website may allow third parties to download cookies onto your device.  Third parties, such as analytics firms and business partners (including Google) may use cookies and other technologies (including Google Analytics) to collect information about your online activities while you are on our website.  This information may be used to measure usage of our website and personalise advertising content on our website.  We do not have access to or control over cookies or other features these third parties may use, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy.  Please refer to the privacy policies of those third parties to better understand their activities and practices.

_Google Analytics_ : We use features of Google Analytics in accordance with the _How We Use Cookies_ section.  For more details on how Google Analytics functions, please refer to Google’s Privacy Policy.  According to its own policy, Google does not collect any personal data using Google Analytics.  Nevertheless, if you do not want to use the remarketing feature from Google, you can disable it by changing the appropriate settings at [http://www.google.com/settings/ads](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__www.google.com_settings_ads&d=DwMGaQ&c=2s2mvbfY0UoSKkl6_Ol9wg&r=pX-B_49T9tUaArbGJal2D6FM2JNUdp6mX4DbVUxcLJM&m=c2tcbKtD7kYgwHvMkHwpVRASs_AjrBvSUxcFBgUjErg&s=dYKEAFC5VAwOs0mApR7_Th1kW6b7Pg9gA1tkK5f6WSI&e=).   

**Personal Data**

We may collect certain types of personal data. As used in this Policy, “personal data” means data, whether true or not, about an individual who can be identified: (a) from that data; or (b) from that data and other information to which the organisation (in this case MBS, all Sands’ subsidiaries and all the third parties of relevance mentioned in this Privacy Policy) has or is likely to have access.  Personal data includes, among other things, your: name; street or mailing address; telephone number(s); email addresses; date of birth; gender; nationality; passport number, date and place of issue; NRIC number; driver’s licence number and expiration; voice, photographs, images, and gaming activity; reservation information; dates of stay; travel history; guest and room preferences; purchases of products and services; payment information; credit card information; marketing preferences; preferred communication methods; reviews and opinions about MBS (if they are identified or associated with you); frequent flyer or travel partner program affiliation and member numbers; hotel, airline and rental car packages booked; groups with which you are associated for reservations and group discounts; location (for location-based mobile applications); participation in a membership or loyalty program, such as Sands Rewards Club or Sands Rewards Lifestyle; answers you provide to security questions (such as your mother’s maiden name, the name of your pet, etc.); information used to provide products or services; information needed to administer rewards or loyalty programs, including transaction and correspondence details; and any other types of information that you choose to provide to us or that we may collect about you through your transactions with MBS or Sands Properties websites.

We may collect additional personal data about you that you knowingly and voluntarily provide in connection with certain activities at or transactions with MBS or our website, such as participation in certain meetings and events, participation in social media offerings (such as signing up through our Facebook pages), use of MBS’ mobile applications, reservations for or use of on-site services (such as entertainment, gaming and other activities), applications for employment, and liability claims.  For example, if you apply for credit at MBS or our websites, we may collect information to process your credit line request, including your identification number, bank account and other financial information, and employment information.  The additional information that we collect depends on the nature of the activity or transaction or how you are interacting with our website.

We may also collect information that is not personally identifiable by themselves, but can be linked to personal data you provide to us. Such information includes the type of Internet browser you are using, your device MAC address, the pages you visited on our websites, how you arrived at our websites ( _i.e_., through a search engine or a referring website), etc.

**Situations where we collect your information:**

_When you enroll in our loyalty program_ , we may collect your name, title, date of birth, and email address.

_When you inform us of your application for credit extension_ , we may collect your credit information including your name, mailing address, email address, phone number, date of birth, credit score, employment information, financial information, including bank account and bank rating information, supporting your eligibility to receive credit, other lines of casino credit in your name, and other information you provide to us to assist us in making a determination concerning extending credit to you.

_When you are at the MBS property, we_ use closed circuit television and other security systems to monitor other public or sensitive areas of our properties for safety and security, as well as, all gaming areas as required by the applicable local regulatory gaming authorities.  Video surveillance cameras are used to protect us, our guests, and our employees.  We monitor our surveillance cameras, and may share surveillance footage with law enforcement and/or regulatory authorities.

_When you complete an employment application_ , we may collect your name or aliases, current and previous, mailing address information, current and previous, email address, phone number, date of birth, employment history, credit history, education, training, and skills, including licenses and certificates, convictions for felonies or misdemeanors, proof of eligibility to work in the United States, military service, and any other information provided in your employment application form.

_When you make a reservation booking at the MBS hotel, we may collect your_ personal data, whether it be through our websites, by phone, or in person at one of our properties, to complete your reservation request.  We also may need to collect information to comply with local laws, including your full name, nationality and passport number.  If you choose to provide it, we also may collect additional information from you, including your frequent flyer or travel partner program information.

When you check in _at the MBS hotel, we may_ ask whether you wish to receive promotional and other marketing materials, including your interest in participating in contests, promotional offers, or using certain services we can provide to you, such as membership in our loyalty program.  We also may send surveys to you to learn more about your stay and preferences.  You may withdraw your consent to receive marketing and promotional materials at any time.

_During your_ stay _at the MBS hotel,_ we record your itemised spending related to your reservation.  This includes your room rate, other expenses billed to your room, food and beverage preferences, and other special requests.  We collect and record this information to keep a record of your expenses and preferences during your stay and provide it to you upon check-out.

**Other Sources of Data**

Other parties may provide your information to us so that we can provide products and services and use your information for purposes listed in the _How We May Use Your Information_ section.  Some situations of such data sharing are set out below.

_Vendors, Suppliers, and Others Doing Business with Us_ :  We have strict rules in place to comply with the laws that apply to us.  Before we do business with a third party, we take reasonable steps to make sure that they will prudently protect the information we share with each other, including your personal data they may collect or receive.

_Casino Credit_ :  For guests who request casino credit from us or our affiliates, we may collect/check, or hire a third party to collect/check, public records available about you.  We must collect this information to comply with the law, and to protect against financial risk.

_Meetings, Incentives, Conferences and Exhibitions (MICE)_ :  We may collect your data through events you attend with our exhibitor clients at any of our MICE event spaces.  When you attend an event and provide personal data during the registration process to exhibitors, we may have access to your personal data because we collect certain information from the exhibitors.

_Third Parties Authorised By You_ :  When someone else arranges for you to interact with our properties, they may provide us information so that we can provide you with products and/or services during your visit.  For example, when your employer or a travel agent arranges for you to stay at one of our properties, they may provide us with the information listed above so that we can provide you with products and services.

## Age Policy

Persons under the age of twenty-one (21) are not permitted to gamble at MBS or enter our casino areas.

Our websites are not intended for persons under the age of 21.  If you are under the age of twenty-one (21) you may not use our website.

## How We May Use Your Information

**Your privacy is important to us.   We collect and use or disclose information we believe is necessary to our business, and to provide you with the products, services, and experiences you expect when you interact with us.  When we collect and use your information, we take your privacy and security very seriously.**

We collect personal data to deliver superior quality of service.  We will use the information you provide to us for the purpose you provided it to us ( _e.g.,_  to make a reservation, pay for a service, apply for casino credit,  _etc._ ), which is stated when information is collected.  We may also use your information in other ways for our business purposes and to provide you with the products, services, and experiences you request and expect from us, including but not limited to the following purposes:

  * To fully respond to your questions, requests, or communications;
  * To verify your identity;
  * To process guest reservations and/or requests for information or services;
  * To provide you with any Sands’ products and services, including but not limited to administering your loyalty membership and benefits including extending cross-property Sands promotions to you;
  * To provide you with personalised content on our website and to improve the content and the navigability of our website;
  * To check if you qualify for certain any Sands’ offers or services (e.g., casino credit, special events, promotional offers, etc.) and to process payment and billing for products and services
  * To record and track gaming activity, including assessing your play and providing comps and other benefits;
  * To improve and personalise the guest experience for you and others;
  * To develop new Sands’ products and services;
  * To audit, research and conduct analysis in order to maintain and improve our services and protect our guests and patrons;
  * To conduct statistical or demographic analysis, marketing and promotions planning and execution, market research and analysis, customer satisfaction and quality assurance surveys;
  * To consider your job application;
  * To ensure the technical functioning and security of our network;
  * To take steps to ensure and monitor safety and security and protection of your personal data, including working with third parties to help protect your information;
  * To comply with applicable laws and regulations, court orders or other legal processes or other legal requirements of any governmental authorities, and to assist our contracting parties’ to comply with the same;
  * To defend and protect the rights or property of sands, its employees, and its guests and patrons; and/or
  * To facilitate a change in the business structure or ownership of MBS or its assets, in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer, or other disposition of all or any portion of Sands’ business, assets, or stock, including any bankruptcy or similar proceedings
  * To respond to exceptional circumstances, such as a national emergency, security concern, or other situation in which MBS deems disclosure of your information as prudent.

If you have ceased to be our customer or client and have cancelled your account or membership, we will not send you marketing materials or share your personal data with unrelated third parties.  However, we may still retain your records and use your information for legal and/or business purposes, including for compliance with any applicable laws.

## Who We Share Information With

We may share information about you to the third parties (whether located within or outside of Singapore) as indicated below for the purposes set out in the  _How We May Use Your Information  _section.

  * Our Sands affiliates;
  * Sands’ Agents and Service Providers who help us to provide some of our products and services or organize events ( _e.g._ , maintenance, IT and telecommunications support, website hosting and operations, distribution of newsletters and marketing materials, analysis, audit, payments, insurance, promotions, marketing, development, credit, reservations, security, to operate any of our businesses or our website).  For example, from time to time we may run promotions or marketing efforts, such as contests, sweepstakes, and/or giveaways with third parties.  If you choose to participate in any such promotions, then any personal data you provide in order to participate may be shared with those third parties and be subject to their privacy policies.  Unless we tell you differently or as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, our agents are expected not to have the right to use your information beyond what is needed to assist us;
  * Governmental authorities, regulatory agencies, statutory boards, government officials, law enforcement authorities, industry associations, legal process participants such as our legal advisers, courts, or other alternative dispute forums; and/or
  * Any third party in connection with any proposed or actual changes in our business structure or ownership, for example, in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer, or other disposition of all or any portion of Sands’ business, assets, or stock (including any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).  

_Sale of Information_ : In the future, we may sell some or all of our assets.  In such transactions, customer information is generally one of the transferred business assets.  In the event of a sale of any of MBS’ assets including customer information, we will require the buyers to honour our Privacy Policy or provide you with notice and an option to limit sharing of your information.

_International Transfers of Information_ : We operate our website in Singapore and we may transfer personal data to the Non-Singapore Sands Properties and our affiliates in Macau or the United States.  Please note that the United States, Macao, and Singapore currently are not on the list of countries that the European Commission considers adequate regarding the protection of personal data.  Regardless, we have taken steps to ensure that appropriate levels of protection necessary to maintain the security and integrity of your personal data are in place and that any transferred data is processed in accordance with the PDPA and any other applicable law.

We may share anonymous or aggregate information among all Sands entities and with third parties, including advertisers, investors, and partners. Aggregate or anonymous information does not contain any personal data, and accordingly its use and disclosure is not subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Note on third party websites – Our website may contain links to third party websites, which are not controlled by us and which are not covered by this Privacy Policy.  You are responsible for reviewing the privacy policies of all such third parties, and we recommend that you read those policies very carefully before disclosing your personal data to any third party, whether directly or indirectly.

## How We Protect Your Personal Data

We strive to take appropriate security measures to help safeguard your personal data from unauthorised access and disclosure.  For example, only authorised employees are allowed to access personal data, and they may only access it for permitted business functions.  We also use technology to protect your information, including encrypting sensitive personal data that is transferred to or from our systems and using firewalls to help prevent unauthorised persons from accessing information.  If you have an online account with us, your account is also protected by a password for your privacy and security, and you must prevent unauthorised access to your account and personal data by selecting and protecting your password appropriately, limiting access to your devices, and by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.

While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse, or alteration of information will never occur, we use reasonable efforts to prevent it.  Please keep in mind that no method of storage or transmission over the Internet is completely secure, so your use of our products and services and provision of information to us is at your own risk.

Please be aware that our websites may contain links to other sites on the Internet that are owned and operated by third parties. The information practices of those websites linked to our websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of websites to which our website links. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your personal data may apply. We strongly suggest you review such third party's privacy policies before providing any data to them.

## Your Choices Regarding Your Information

_To Update or Correct Your Information_ : **** You may request to correct (including update) your information by submitting a form which can be found at <https://www.marinabaysands.com/Company-Information/Data-Protection-Office/>

_To Access Your Information_ : **** You may request to access your information by submitting a form which can be found at [https://www.marinabaysands.com/Company-Information/Data-Protection-Office/](http://www.marinabaysands.com/Company-Information/Data-Protection-Office/). Where permitted by law, we may charge a reasonable administrative fee for this service.  Please note that subject to the PDPA, not all information that we have collected may be available for review. 

_To Withdraw Consent or Object_ :  You may request for us to cease to process your personal data at any time for any purpose(s) by submitting the appropriate withdrawal of consent form which can be found at <http://www.marinabaysands.com/Company-Information/Data-Protection-Office/>.  Alternatively, if you have provided us with your email address and you would like to stop receiving marketing emails from us, you may click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of our email communications.  Please note that if you withdraw or decline your consent for a limited purpose, such as for marketing or a specific category of marketing, we may still contact you or use your information for other purposes for which you have not withdrawn your consent and such personal data may still be shared, as permitted under the PDPA and other applicable law.

## Note To Residents of the EU, EEA, and Switzerland

If you reside or otherwise find yourself in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), European Union (“EU”), or Switzerland, we are committed to respecting your rights as a data subject under the applicable laws of these countries.  For all personal data that we have about you, please note the following:

_Automated Decision-making_ :  We may use automated decision-making to determine whether job applicants meet the required qualifications.  You have the right to have a human involved in this process, to express your point of view, and to contest the decision.  You may do so by using the method in the  _Contact Us_  section below.

_Data Portability, Imposing Restrictions on Data Processing, Data Erasure_ :  If you would like to request that we provide a copy of your information to you or restrict processing of your information or erase it, please contact us using the method in the  _Contact Us_  section below.

_Responding to Requests_ :  Each request to access, correct, restrict processing, erase, or provide a copy of data will be evaluated to determine whether the requested change meets legal regulatory requirements and does not risk making our other data less secure or changing our other data.  Please note that we will require you to provide us with proof of identity and address before responding to your requests to exercise such rights.

_Complaints to Supervisory Authority_ :  You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority of the European Union or European Economic Area according to that authority’s rules and procedures.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify or change this Privacy Policy at any time. The Effective Date, as stated above, indicates the last time this policy was materially revised. When we make a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will inform you by posting a prominent notice on the home page of our website or changing the date on this page noting when the Privacy Policy was last updated. We encourage you to review this page periodically to understand our policy regarding the collection and use of your personal data.

Your continued use of our website and acceptance of our services at MBS after any changes to this Privacy Policy constitutes your consent to any such changes, to the extent such consent is not otherwise provided.

## Contact Us

For questions regarding this Privacy policy or if you have a privacy concern or questions about how your personal data is used, please contact us at DataProtectionOfficer@MarinaBaySands.com.
